<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2014 Zbigniew Jędrzejewski-Szmek <zbyszek@in.waw.pl> -->
<component type="desktop">
  <id>emacs.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0+</project_license>
  <name>GNU Emacs</name>
  <summary>Edit text files, view pictures and binary files</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Emacs is a powerful, customizable, self-documenting, modeless
      editor. It is used primarely to edit text, including text
      documents, source code of programs, web pages and XML documents,
      but can also be used to display and edit binary files.
    </p>
    <p>
      Emacs allows efficient editing of text with shortcuts which
      allow operating on letters, words, sentences, and paragraphs as
      single units. This includes both moving around and operations
      like copying, deleting, transposing, and pasting. Macros can be
      conveniently defined to repeat sequences of commands. In
      addition, Emacs is (partially) built in a scripting language
      (elisp) which can also be used to define further functions
      extending existing capabilities.
    </p>
    <p>
      Emacs has extensive support for editing source code, including
      programmable syntax highlighting, automatic indentation, source
      code indexing, overview modes, and navigation based on language
      specific units like functions and blocks. It is also possible to
      invoke the compiler from within Emacs and easily move between
      compiler output and corresponding positions in the source.
    </p>
    <p>
      Emacs has multiple modules which provide further functionality.
      This provides the capability to read mail, news, browse
      pictures, read man and info pages, browse the web, execute
      arbitrary programs, and more, without leaving the editor.
    </p>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default" height="888" width="1595">
      <image>http://in.waw.pl/~zbyszek/fedora/emacs-two-buffers.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot height="667" width="1199">
      <image>http://in.waw.pl/~zbyszek/fedora/emacs-editing-xml.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot height="572" width="1019">
      <image>http://in.waw.pl/~zbyszek/fedora/emacs-hexl-mode.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot height="667" width="1199">
      <image>http://in.waw.pl/~zbyszek/fedora/emacs-showing-svg.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot height="439" width="794">
      <image>http://in.waw.pl/~zbyszek/fedora/emacs-with-python-source.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/html_node/emacs/Bugs.html</url>
  <url type="donation">https://my.fsf.org/donate/</url>
  <url type="help">https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/manual/</url>
  <update_contact>zbyszek@in.waw.pl</update_contact>
  <translation/>
</component>
